<!-- 
possible types:
 - path
 - filename
 - string
 - boolean (yes/no)
 - uint
 - enum('','','')

possible usages:
 - basic
 - advanced
 - debug
-->
<configuration>
	<section name="General">
		<key name="ModulesDirectory" type="path" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies the path to modules directory. The MPEG-4 Systems engine cannot be loaded without modules. This option is used by GPAC clients on all platforms. 
		</key>
		<key name="CacheDirectory" type="path" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies location of temp files. The user must have write access to this location. Although not used by applications, this is used by several modules. 
		</key>
		<key name="StartupFile" type="path" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies file to load upon startup of most clients (Osmo4/MP4Client). If not specified, no file is loaded. 
		</key>
		<key name="LogFile" type="path" default="stdout" usage="basic">
			Specifies where to output GPAC's log. By default, the logs are written to stdout. Note that GPAC may be compiled without log support. This is not used by MP4Client. 
		</key>
		<key name="Logs" type="string" default="error@all" usage="basic">
			Specifies log level for each tool, with the following syntax: <br></br>
			tool[:tool]@level:tool[:tool]@level<br></br>
			By default, only errors are logged.<br></br>
			Available levels are: 
			<ul>
			<li><i>quiet</i> : no logging is performed on the tool</li>
			<li><i>error</i> : only errors are logged</li>
			<li><i>warning</i> : warnings are also logged.</li>
			<li><i>info</i> : information messages are also logged</li>
			<li><i>debug</i> : debug messages are also logged</li>
			</ul>
			Available tools are:
			<ul>
			<li><i>core</i> : libgpac core</li>
			<li><i>coding</i> : bitstream formats (audio, video, scene)</li>
			<li><i>container</i> : container formats (ISO File, MPEG-2 TS, AVI, ...)</li>
			<li><i>network</i> : network data except RTP trafic</li>
			<li><i>rtp</i> : rtp, rtcp and rtsp trafic</li>
			<li><i>author</i> : authoring tools (hint, import, export)</li>
			<li><i>sync</i> : terminal sync layer</li>
			<li><i>codec</i> : terminal codec messages</li>
			<li><i>parser</i> : scene parsers (svg, xmt, bt) and other</li>
			<li><i>media</i> : terminal media object management</li>
			<li><i>scene</i> : scene graph and scene manager</li>
			<li><i>script</i> : scripting engine messages</li>
			<li><i>interact</i> : user interaction messages</li>
			<li><i>compose</i> : composition engine (events, etc)</li>
			<li><i>cache</i> : HTTP cache</li>
			<li><i>mmio</i> : Audio/Video HW I/O management</li>
			<li><i>rti</i> : Run-time info (CPU, mem, ...)</li>
			<li><i>smil</i> : SMIL timing and animation</li>
			<li><i>memory</i> : GPAC memory tracker</li>
			<li><i>audio</i> : Audio renderer and mixers</li>
			<li><i>module</i> : used by some modules</li>
			<li><i>mutex</i> : mutex information</li>
			<li><i>console</i> : console messages, such as script alert() and error notifications</li>
			</ul>
		</key>
		<key name="Loop" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies whether the presentation has to be restarted when done playing. 
		</key>
		<key name="ConsoleOff" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies whether application messages (script, buffering, download progress) are displayed in the console or not. 
		</key>
		<key name="SingleInstance" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies if the player should be a single instance application or not (Osmo4-Win32 only). 
		</key>
		<key name="LookForSubtitles" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies if Osmo4 shall look for subtitle files when opening a presentation. 
		</key>
		<key name="ViewXMT" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies if scene dumping shall be done in XML (XMT, X3D) or in VRML-like syntax (BT, WRL). 
		</key>
		<key name="ConfigPanel" type="uint" default="0" usage="basic">
			Specifies the latest config panel selected by user. 
		</key>
		<key name="NoMIMETypeFetch" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies if the player has to check for mime type when following hyperlinks, or only follow links of known extensions. 
		</key>
		<key name="PLEntry" type="uint" default="1" usage="basic">
			Indicates active playlist entry when player was last closed. Playlist backup is: 
			<ul>
				<li>"gpac_pl.m3u" on win32 platforms, stored in same directory as application</li>
				<li>".gpac_pl.m3u" on other platforms, stored in user home directory</li>
			</ul>
		</key>
		<key name="FillScreen" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies if the display area shall fill all available space on screen. WindowsMobile/Symbian only 
		</key>
		<key name="DisableBackLight" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies if the screen backlighting shall be disabled while playing. WindowsMobile/Symbian only 
		</key>
		<key name="LastWorkingDir" type="path" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies the directory of the last local file opened. Smartphone Windows only 
		</key>
		<key name="Browser" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies prefered browser for WWW anchors and scene graph viewing - Only used by Osmo4/wxWidgets.
		</key>
	</section>
	<section name="RecentFiles">
		The "RecentFiles" section of the config file holds last accessed files (hardcoded to no more than 20) in the last access order. The keys are the file names and no value is used. This section is only used by GUI clients (osmo4/wxOsmo4) 
	</section>
	<section name="Systems">
		<key name="LanguageName" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies the user prefered language in readable english. This is used to select streams in case of alternate content in an audio object. 
		</key>
		<key name="Language3CC" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies the user prefered language as expressed in ISO 639-2. This is used to select streams in case of alternate content in an audio object. 
		</key>
		<key name="Language2CC" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies the user prefered language as expressed in ISO 639-1. This is used to select streams in case of alternate content in an audio object. 
		</key>		
		<key name="DrawLateFrames" type="" default="yes" usage="basic">
			If set, late frames will still be drawn. If not set, the late frames are droped (or executed for systems decoders) until the decoder output is back in sync. This is by default on to keep better testing heavy content or slow renderers, but should be set to off when needing a better sync or monitoring skipped frames. 
		</key>
		<key name="ForceSingleClock" type="" default="no" usage="basic">
			One big problem with MP4 files is that the notion of "duration" has been unclear for a long time, and most content available (audio-video files) specify a wrong BIFS duration. In such a case the movie cannot be controled/seeked into. Another problem with ISMA streaming is that BIFS/OD don't use the same clock as audio/video, thus seeking the main timeline does not seek AV media. Setting the ForceSingleClock will handle both cases by using a single timeline for all media streams and setting the duration to the one of the longest stream
		</key>
		<key name="ThreadingPolicy" type="enum('Free', 'Single', 'Multi')" default="Free" usage="basic">
			Specifies how media decoders are to be threaded. "Free" lets decoders decide of their threading, "Single" means that all decoders are managed in a single thread performing scheduling and priority handling and "Multi" means that each decoder runs in its own thread. 
		</key>
		<key name="Priority" type="enum('low','normal','high','real-time')" default="normal" usage="basic">
			Specifies the priority of the decoders (priority is applied to decoder thread(s) regardless of threading mode). 
		</key>
		<key name="TimeSlice" type="uint" default="0" usage="basic">
			Specifies the target maximum time (in ms) of one cycle of the media manager (the media manager will attempts to call all the active decoders within this time. Depending on the threading mode this option can be ignored.
		</key>
		<key name="ModuleUnload" type="boolean" default="yes" usage="basic">
			Specifies whether modules should be unloaded if not used or not. Default: "yes". 
		</key>
		<key name="ResyncLateClock" type="uint" default="0" usage="basic">
			Specifies the threshold after which late clocks are resynchronized to timestamps for OCR streams. By default, no threashold (0) is used and clocks are never resynchronized. This allows to resync clocks to the media owning the clock when the decoding is really too slow, and should only be used for debugging purposes. 
		</key>
		<key name="NoVisualThread" type="boolean" default="no" usage="basic">
			Specifies whether the visual rendering is done in the main codec manager or in a dedicated thread. 
		</key>
		<key name="DefAudioDec" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies which module to use by default for audio decoding. The string is the name of the module to be used (same considerations as other modules, cf introduction). 
		</key>
		<key name="DefVideoDec" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies which module to use by default for video decoding. The string is the name of the module to be used (same considerations as other modules, cf introduction). 
		</key>
		<key name="DefImageDec" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Specifies which module to use by default for image decoding. The string is the name of the module to be used (same considerations as other modules, cf introduction). 
		</key>
		<key name="codec_*" type="string" default="" usage="basic">
			Allows to specify default media module (audio/video) per stream type and object type. This is useful if you have more than one decoder for a given type (ex, XviD and FFMPEG for MPEG-4 visual SP). The syntax is:<br></br>
			codec_AA_BB=modulename<br></br>
			where AA is the hexadecimal MPEG-4 streamType value for the codec (04=visual, 05=audio) and BB is the hexadecimal MPEG-4 objectTypeIndication of the media (0x20 = MPEG-4 video, 0x40=MPEG-4 Audio, ...). The string is the name of the module to be used (same considerations as other modules, cf introduction). 
		</key>
 	</section>
	<section name="Network">
		<key name="BufferLength" type="uint" default="3000" usage="basic">
			Specifies the length of the decoding buffer in milliseconds. The client will wait for the buffer to be filled before starting decoding. A module may decide to use a different value based on protocol and network jitters.
		</key>
 	</section>
	<section name="DASH">
		<key name="LowLatency" type="enum('always', 'chunk', 'no')" default="no" usage="basic">
			Sets low-latency mode enabled. In low-latency mode, media data is parsed as soon as possible while segment is being downloaded. Default is no. If chunk is selected, media data is re-parsed at each HTTP 1.1 chunk end. If always is selected, media data is re-parsed as soon as HTTP data is received.
		</key>
 	</section>
</configuration>
